# **Paul Kenny**

Phone: +353 (0)85 7531623 Email: paulkenny2@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I have developed numerous programs in college using Java and SQL and some in C++. I have long term experience with dealing with customers and clients in my previous employment positions, including over ten years' experience in the Structural Engineering industry. I am an ICT student with previous employment experience in various industries and strong interpersonal skills seeking a work placement position.

#### IT SKILLS

- Confident user of Java
- Can write SQL queries to intermediate level using Oracle 10G & administer an Oracle 10G database server using SQL Developer and related SQL commands.
- Can design and create database schemas
- Capable of designing developing websites using Bootstrap, JavaScript, CSS and HTML
- Competent user of Windows and Linux Operating Systems in system administration.
- Design, build and troubleshoot a network using routers and switches
- Configure a router using the Cisco IOS command set
- Quality Assurance and Testing of Software.
- Utilise the Object Oriented approach to Software Design.

#### **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

### 2013 - to-date BSc Information Technology Management

Institute of Technology Tallaght, Dublin 24

1st Year Modules studied, Web & User Experience (A), Computer Architecture (A), Discrete Mathematics 1 (A), Business & Information Systems (A), Software Development 1 (A), Learning to Learn at Third Level (A), Software Development 2 (A), Object Oriented System Analysis (A), Database Fundamentals (A), Operating Systems Fundamentals (A), Statistics (A), Social Media Communications (A).

2<sup>nd</sup> Year Modules studied, Software Development 3 (A), Software Quality Assurance & Testing (A), Networking 1 (A), Database Design & Programming (A), Discrete Mathematics 2 (A), Web Design & Development 1 (A), Software Development 4 (A), Project (A), Networking 2 (A), Management Science (A), Object Oriented Analysis & Design 1 (A), Information Security (A).

**3**<sup>rd</sup> **Year Modules Studied**, Cloud Service & Distributed Computing **(B)**, Web Design & Development 2 **(A)**, Algorithms & Data Structures 1 **(B+)**, Operating Systems **(B+)**, Advanced Database **(A)**, Innovation & Enterprise **(B+)**, Mini-Project **(C+)**, Experimental Learning **(PASS)**.

# Significant Projects Undertaken

### "Drifting" Fan Club Web Site

## Description

A two-person web project designed to allow fans of Drift Racing access to information, news and events related to the Irish and International scene. This involved creating a hierarchical structured web site using HTML, CSS and Play Framework (building applications with Java & Scala).

#### Challenges faced:

Writing an extensive research and testing report, including extensive storyboarding (PowerPoint).

## **Technologies & Tools Used:**

HTML, CSS, Play Framework

### **Cinema Ticket Booking System**

# Description

A group project designed to handle cinema ticket booking and allocation. The system could handle multiple users, both customers and management, who could edit and modify profiles, files and data stored in a database. The project was written in Java and Java Swing and utilized SQL queries to access an Oracle 10g database.

### **Challenges faced:**

- Utilise the Object Oriented approach to design the class structure of the program.
- Creating an interface between the Java program and Oracle Database.
- Writing complex SQL queries to glean very specific information from the Oracle Database.

# **Technologies & Tools Used:**

Java, Java Swing, Oracle 10g Database.

# Responsive Corporate Website for OpenJaw Technologies

#### Description

An individual mini-project designed to recreate OpenJaw Technologies corporate website to make it responsive to different physical platforms. The website could responsively reformat its layout to suit the accessing platform (phone, tablet, PC). The project was written in HTML and CSS.

# Challenges faced:

- Rewriting and recreating the website from scratch.
- Creating HTML layouts that would react dynamically to the accessing platform using advanced CSS.

#### **Technologies & Tools Used:**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

May 1991 – July 2001 Structural Engineering Technician Hendrick Ryan & Assoc. **Company Description:** Civil/Structural Engineers with extensive experience in the design and construction of multi-million-euro Hotel, Residential, Leisure, Commercial, Institutional and Industrial projects. http://www.hra.ie

### Main Responsibilities

<u>Creating Structural Eng. drawings from architectural plans and dealing with clients</u>

Working closely in a team of Engineers and technicians to translate architectural drawings to Structural Engineering drawings using AutoCad. Creating detailed scheduling reports of Reinforced Concrete and Structural Steelwork. Working to precise deadlines. Dealing directly with clients, both face to face and via phone and e-mail, to resolve issues and requests they may have had regarding current in-progress accounts.

July 2001 - May 2012

Various Production and Manufacturing Roles including:

Irish Distillers Limited/ Pernod-Ricard

**Company Description:** Irish Distillers is a subsidiary of the French drinks conglomerate Pernod-Ricard S.A.. It is the largest distiller of Irish Whiskey, with popular brands such as Jameson, Paddy and Powers. In addition to manufacturing and distilling Irish Distillers also distributes Pernod-Richard flagship wines and spirits through Ireland. <a href="http://www.irishdistillers.ie">http://www.irishdistillers.ie</a>

# Main Responsibilities

Production line operator. Order preparation.

Working within a team of master distillers, production managers and production line operatives to prepare, bottle and distribute Irish Distillers array of spirits.

February 2016 – September 2016 Software Development Intern OpenJaw Technologies.

Company Description: Software Development company who specialize in developing t-Retail software for the travel industry.

http://www.openjawtech.com/

# Main Responsibilities

Software Development Intern

Working closely in a team of software development engineers to create and maintain OpenJaw Technologies t-Retail platform. Working to precise deadlines. Working in an agile development environment.

#### **INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

**Pastimes** 

• I play Pitch & Putt, Snooker and Darts regularly. In the past I have also been a member of several Pool teams and played in local Dublin tournaments.

### Professional

- City & Guilds Certificate with distinction in Structural Engineering.
- City & Guilds Certificate with distinction in Business Skills.

### **REFERENCES**

Available on request